Nicholas Kammer, CPA

Fort Myers, FL | kammer@gmail.com | Github: https://github.com/ScroogesMoneybin | Website: NAEK2.com

SUMMARY

AI Tech co-Founder. Chief Data Officer. Detail-oriented researcher/programmer with experience in financial and investment assets, management, investment banking, mergers & acquisitions, valuations, data analysis.

Computer/Data Analytics programming experience in Javascript, React, Node, AWS, Python, SQL, R, Tableau, & LLMs.

EDUCATION

MIT

MicroMasters program in Statistics and Data Science - Online

University of Pennsylvania2019 - 2021Master of Arts in Near Eastern Languages & CivilizationsGPA 4.00/4.00

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

Master of Science in Accountancy

Awards: Phi Kappa Phi

Brown University
Bachelor's degrees in Mathematics, Mathematical-Economics, and Egyptology
GPA: 3.81/4.00

Awards: Magna cum Laude Phi Beta Kappa

WORK EXPERIENCE

Chief Data & AI Officer and Co-Founder

2024 - Present

May 2004 GPA:3.97/4.00

Politech AI

- Co-founded data-driven AI and LLM-focused Marketing Tech company
- Oversee and lead all company data and AI-focused projects
- Designed, built, and deployed all data-related technology and deliverables
 - o Developed customized dashboards and data visualizations for clients
 - O Developed spatially-constrained clustering model to determine dense groupings in a geographic region to optimize targeting of best potential customers
 - o Personally chose LLM model and designed prompts to allow effective online marketing outreach
 - o Built raking algorithm, using R, to rebalance data from web scraping to better align with target demographics
 - Used neural net algorithm with past successful customers to determine new potential targets from broader pool
- Coordinate with my data team and the software developers to launch and maintain new AI and data technology
- Utilize SQL for custom data pulls from company database for use in algorithms
- Deployed custom deliverables via Github, AWS and Shiny Server

Instructor of Data Analytics Bootcamp

2023 - Present

Upright Education

- Teach online Bootcamp students, covering Python, R, Tableau, SQL, and Excel data analytics topics
- Break down complex data analytics into understandable blocks of information that new students can comprehend
- Develop code outlines to walk students through new technical concepts
- Illustrate SQL logic using online code question repositories, such as Leetcode
- Prepare material and lead instruction for 2 separate cohorts 3 nights a week after regular job for a total of 18 hours a week of instruction
- Hold weekly tutorial sessions to supplement the week's topics and ensure student understanding
- Manage class organization, track student engagement, and check student homework
- Assist students in planning and executing their individualized Capstone projects

Acceptionally.com

- Online e-commerce site storefront for Nancy's Boutique
 - o Nancy's Boutique is an online multi-platform retail storefront, selling clothing and household items
 - Nancy's Boutique also distributes through Amazon, eBay, and Facebook Marketplace in addition to Acceptionally.com
- Built with ReactJS site using Redux and Redux Saga on the front-end and utilizes a Netlify serverless functions for deployment
- Processes payments through Stripe Payment Element
- Incorporates Google Firebase and Firestore database
- Includes Progressive Web App (PWA) functionality

Professor 2021 - 2023

Ave Maria University

- Professor of Mathematics
 - o Taught College Algebra and Calculus for over 150 students at a time
 - Advised students on outside classes (such as computer programming) to give themselves the best career opportunities
 - Created PowerPoint presentations for each topic covered and posted them to Canvas website for easy access
 - o Held lengthy sessions outside office hours and class for tutoring and make-up quizzes and exams
 - Utilized Microsoft Teams to tutor students who could not attend regular in-person meetings or tutoring
- Counseled students with career planning advice
- Mentored students on Javascript
- Professor of Accounting
 - o Taught Managerial Accounting
 - o Oversaw student projects designing their hypothetical businesses and building Master Budgets
 - Created PowerPoint presentations for each topic covered and posted them to Canvas website for easy access
 - Assisted AMU's career services in networking with local businesses to expand job opportunities for graduates
 - o Advised Business School administration on enhancing the undergraduate data analytics program
 - Advised about the appropriate programming tools and languages to emphasize to improve student job placement
 - Researched opportunities to expand in-class learning tools from Tableau
 - Utilized Microsoft Teams to tutor students who could not attend regular in-person meetings or tutoring

Private Investment Analyst and Trader

2017 – Present

- Managed portfolio of stock and option trades to maximize profits
- Evaluated investment vehicles with emphasis on growth opportunities
- Utilized databases and chart analysis to analyze investment data to select best opportunities
- Manage private trust assets for the benefit of beneficiaries
- Researched new opportunities, including:
 - o Private company angel investments for clients
 - o Advised on the potential of developing exotic asset opportunities for clients

NAEK2, LLC

Valuation Consultant 2008 – 2012

- Worked as a consultant, analyzing start-up companies early in development, especially at the Research Park connected with the University of Illinois' entrepreneur incubator
- Prepared financial statements and projections for the purposes of strategic planning, presentations to awards committees, and recruitment of potential investors
- Performed valuations for companies to determine fair valuations in negotiations with investors, utilizing methods such as:
 - Market-based valuation

- Discounted cash flow
- Closely-held business valuation
- o Minority ownership discounting

Dresner Partners Investment Bank

Analyst

- Worked primarily in Mergers and Acquisitions on the sell side
- Developed valuation models such as NPV, LBO, and market comparables to determine fair value of client companies for sale negotiations
- Recruited businesses as clients on the sell side
- Researched and recruited potential buyers for client companies

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

NAEK2.com

- Personal website
- Contains selection of Javascript, ReactJS, Typescript, and Solidity projects

Generative AI Document Analysis App

- Document analysis tool written in Python, utilizing Langchain, Chroma vector database, and Generative AI Large Language Model (one version with ChatGPT and another version with Google's Bard AI)
- Allows user uploading of personal documents for analysis
- User can ask questions of the AI about the document
- Adjustable parameters available to give more or less detailed AI responses
- Link to apps is on personal website under Projects: naek2.com

Launched Private Blockchain Network

- Utilized geth to initialize and launch private blockchain on the Goerli test network of Ethereum
- Created Externally Owned Account
- Initiated mining for the private blockchain

Dispersion Study of Book of the Dead Spells using Tableau

- Utilized Tableau to track and investigate the geospatial and temporal diffusion of spells from the Book of the Dead in Ancient Egypt
- Mapped the sources of every object with Book of the Dead spells by specified criteria using Tableau's geolocation features
- Cross-analyzed the artifacts by time period, location, gender of the owner, and quantity.
- Performed trend analysis through the time periods to see how dispersion developed chronologically

Develop Database of Ancient Egyptian Coffin Texts

- Compiled, digitized, and cleaned over 6,000 lines of data on funerary texts from old, out-of-print research compendiums to allow broader access to researchers
- Joined data from multiple databases into a broader database for more efficient analysis as .csv and Excel files
- On-going process
 - o Current work has been on data from only one time period
 - o Database will be expanded to include funerary texts from across multiple time periods, including the Pyramid Texts of the Old Kingdom, the Coffin Texts of the Middle Kingdom, and the Book of the Dead from the New Kingdom and Ptolemaic Period

Classification of MNIST Digits and Multi-digits using Python

2004 - 2008

- Implemented a variety of data science methodologies in Python to study the famous MNIST database and compare methodologies as applied to the database
 - o Neural networks both manually built and utilizing PyTorch
 - Fully Connected Neural Network
 - Convolutional Neural Network
 - o Support Vector Machine for multiclass classification
 - o Softmax regression with gradient descent
- Successfully tuned hyperparameters of convolutional neural network using PyTorch to achieve 98.02% accuracy for test set of multi-digit dataset

PROFESSIONAL CREDENTIALS AND AFFILIATIONS

- Certificates in computer programming from ZTM Coding Academy in Javascript, React, Node, Golang, and Network Security
- Registered CPA
- AICPA member since 2004
- Personal Financial Specialist (PFS)
- CANSLIM investing certification
- Foundations of Data Science (Professional Certificate) University of California, Berkeley Online

OUTSIDE INTERESTS

Alumni interviewer for Brown University applicants